Tolles, N. Arnold Papers /3004
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
N. Arnold Tolles Papers
1955-1969
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Tolles, N. Arnold
/3004
3 cubic feet
3 linear ft.
Administrative papers.
Papers of an early facutly member and administrator of the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
3070420
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, March 12, 2015
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, January 14, 2016
Biographical / Historical
N. Arnold Tolles (September 21, 1903 - April 10, 1973) was professor of industrial and labor relations at Cornell's New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
Born in New York City, Tolles was earned his B. Phil ('23), M.S. ('24), and PhD ('32) from the University of Chicago, and his M.S. ('26) from Harvard University. From 1929 to 1935, Tolles taught at Mount Holyoke and Smith College, after which he entered government service through the end of World War II. Tolles held positions in the U.S Bureau of Labor Statistics, the Department of Labor's Wage-House Division, and the Labor Division of the U.S. Advisory Commission to the National Defense Council.
After the conclusion of World War II, Tolles joined the faculty of American University, then in 1947 joined the faculty of the ILR School. Tolles was appointed professor emeritus in 1971. During his long career at Cornell, Tolles published extensively including such work as Origins of Modern Wage Theories (1964), Labor Costs and International Trade (1961), and others.
In addition to teaching, research, and government service, Tolles was involved in local government. A Democrat, he served as alderman in Ithaca from 1965 to 1969, chairman of the Ithaca City Council's Finance Committee in 1968-1969, and member of the Tompkins County Board of Representatives from 1971 until his death in 1973.
See the Cornell University Faculty Memorial Statement for Professor N. Arnold Tolles
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3020 AV: N. Arnold Tolles Memorial Service Audio-Visual Materials
Tolles, N. Arnold.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations --Faculty.
3070420
- Mohasco Layoff Survey (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  1 of 3
- Mohasco Layoff Survey (Box 1, Folder 2)
  2 of 3
- Mohasco Layoff Survey (Box 1, Folder 3)
  3 of 3
- Mohasco Layoff Survey - Serial 51 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Mohasco Layoff Survey - Serial 51 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Mohasco Layoff Survey - Serial 51 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Mohasco Layoff Survey - Serial 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Mohasco Layoff Survey - Serial 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Mohasco Layoff Survey - Serial (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Mohasco Layoff Survey -Serial 702 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Mohasco Layoff Survey - Serial 702 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Mohasco Layoff Survey - Serial 702 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Mohasco Layoff Survey - Serial x140 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  1 of 4
- Mohasco Layoff Survey - Serial x140 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  2 of 4
- Mohasco Layoff Survey - Serial x140 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  3 of 4
- Mohasco Layoff Survey - Serial x140 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  4 or 4
- Mohasco Layoff Survey - Serial 603 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Mohasco Layoff Survey - Serial 603 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Mohasco Layoff Survey - Serial 603 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Mohasco Layoff Survey - Serial 603 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  4 of 4
- Original Ms. And typed copy of lectures given at the University of Munich by N. A. Tolles, at Fulbright Lectures, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Original Ms. And typed copy of lectures given at the University of Munich by N. A. Tolles at Fulbright Lectures, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  manuscripts
- Original Ms. And typed copy of lectures given at the University of Munich by N. A. Tolles, at Fulbright Lectures, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Original Lecture Notes of Tausig Lectures, 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Harvard
- NAT Articles for Encyclopedia of Labor (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Encyclopedia of Labor (M. M. Plumb, ed) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Elmira - Community Wage Survey, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Elmira - Job Descriptions (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Olga Arnold (Box 2, Folder 9)
- NAT - Publicity on Book from 1964 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Taft-Hartley Act (Box 2, Folder 11)
- ILR Bulletin - projected - Foreign Trade (Box 2, Folder 12)
- ILR Review - Dye - Brg. Theory of Res., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- J. of Economic Lit., 1969 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Clague Manuscript
- ILR Review, Gross, A. C. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- ILR Review Community Economic Developments, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Journal of Economic Law, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Haber
- ILR Review Prices, Wages, Turner & Zoeteweij (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Ad. Sc. Quarterly Review "Equit. Payment" (Box 2, Folder 19)
- ILR - Agriculture Bargaining Power (Box 2, Folder 20)
  G. W. Ladd
- Munich Lectures German Booklet (Box 2, Folder 21)
- ILR Review, 6/62 - Morgan Labor Economics (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Review of Turner Ms. Wages in Cam Theory, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Comments on Beal-Wickerham Book, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Ms. Wage Survey Article - ILR Res (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Tolles-Haddy Reprints, Corres & C., 1958 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Tolies - Haddy Paper (Box 2, Folder 27)
- NAT Reviews from 1955 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- AER - Salkever "Wage Structure" Review (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Toless-Hosking Paper - ILR Research, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Tolles - The Social Origins of Recent Wage Theories (Box 2, Folder 31)
  Manuscript
- Chapter X (Box 2, Folder 32)
  Original Manuscripts
- A Social History of Recent Wage Theories (Box 2, Folder 33)
  Arnold Tolles
- Notes on proof (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Notes on Ch. 10, 11, 12 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  Tolles
- Minimum Wage Law Flyers (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Minimum Wage (Box 2, Folder 37)
  chapter 9
- Trade Union Challenge to Wage Theory (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Final Draft (Box 2, Folder 39)
  chapter 4
- Social Worker: Challenge to Wage Theory (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Social Workers Challenge to Wage Theory (Box 3, Folder 2)
  ch. 3, Tolles
- Resolutions of the Faculty of the University of Wisconsin on the death of Emeritus Professor Commons (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Tolles: Challenge to Wage Theory (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Ch. 12 Automation (Box 3, Folder 5)
  draft
- Welfare Capitalism (Box 3, Folder 6)
  ch. 7
- The American Trade Union Challenge to Wage Theory, 1890-1920 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- US Department of Labor - 50th Anniversary, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- BLS - Women's Bureau, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- BLS - Women's Bureau, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- General Cable vs. MESA, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Rome, NY
- Goulds Pumps - Garnsey - Guthrie (Box 3, Folder 12)
  SF
- Paul Douglas (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Committee for a National Trade Policy (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Hight
- Radja Krishna Akhauri, PhD (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Arnold Tolles NY State Certificate of Service (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Microfilm Index (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Student Life at Cornell University (Box 3, Folder 18)
  1 of 2
- Student Life at Cornell University (Box 3, Folder 19)
  2 of 2
- Accreditation (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Re-organization of ILR 348, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- ILR Planning and Records (Box 3, Folder 22)
- ILR Planning Records (Box 3, Folder 23)
- ILR Planning Records (Box 3, Folder 24)
- ILR Planning Records (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Memorandum - Faculty Planning Committee (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Tolles Research (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Tolles Department of Labor (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Tolles Department of Labor (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Tolles Department of Labor (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Tolles Course Materials (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Tolles Lecture Information (Box 3, Folder 32)